Anne Jones

💡 Seattle, WA 🛮 🥆 annejones.dev 🛭 in anneelizjones 🌎 aelizj 🖂 anne.eliz.jones@gmail.com

₽ PROFILE

Software Engineer based in Seattle, Washington, with years of experience developing in JavaScript, Go, and Ruby; and the cocreator of Arroyo, a lightweight framework for the granular rehydration of logs from cloud storage to Elasticsearch. Most recently, Anne developed Flora, a social media platform for plant enthusiasts.

☑ SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, Ruby, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, C#, Java, Bash

Cloud

AWS (ECS, Fargate, ECR, Lambda, S3, SQS, IAM, EC2), Heroku, DigitalOcean (Droplets) Frameworks

React, Redux, MUI, Jest, Express, Sinatra, Vue, Nuxt.js, Tailwind

Technologies

Nginx, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, Node.JS, RESTful APIs, Git/Github

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Creator, Software Engineer @

Flora (www.floraapp.dev)

05/2023 - present

- Designed, architected, and developed Flora, a niche social media platform using React, Redux Toolkit, NodeJS, and Express.
- Integrated MongoDB for robust data storage and implemented secure authentication with Passport, Bcrypt, and JWTs.
- Deployed using AWS ECR, ECS, and Fargate, with an EC2 Load Balancer for traffic management.
- Prioritized idiomatic, maintainable code adhering to industry best practices.
- Implemented a mobile-first approach with MUI, ensuring a seamless user experience across devices.
- Utilized Docker for streamlined deployment and consistency across environments.
- Successfully launched Flora, accessible at floraapp.dev, showcasing comprehensive development acumen.

Backend Engineer 10/2022 - 01/2023

Corvee

- Wrote a traversal algorithm in Go to map a tree-based data structure containing bootstrapping entities to the database
- Enhanced management of user data by building out additional API endpoints in Go that expose further CRUD operations
- Self-started on Vue to migrate core functionality of internal tooling from Vue 2 to Vue 3 so the team could take advantage of Vue 3 feature additions

Co-Creator, Software Engineer @

04/2022 - 09/2022

Arroyo (www.arroyoframework.com)

- Designed, prototyped, and developed Arroyo, a lightweight framework that allows users to granularly rehydrate logs from cloud storage back into Elasticsearch (Node.js, Express.js, React/Redux, AWS, Docker)
- Spearheaded the design and development of the Arroyo Client UI (React/Redux, JavaScript)
- Built scripts to facilitate automated provisioning and teardown of AWS cloud infrastructure, including Lambda, S3, SQS, and IAM roles and policies using AWS SDK
- Facilitated the execution of multiple asynchronous re-ingestion tasks by leveraging Lambda's serverless compute model
- Decoupled and containerized the Arroyo UI and back-end components to simplify deployment and achieve a clean separation
- Created a RESTful API between Arroyo's back end and UI
- Deployed and configured an ELK stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana) on an EC2 instance to optimize testing and development
- Drove daily collaboration with a fully remote team across three different time zones
- Leveraged Agile methodologies to ensure effective daily stand-ups
- Authored and presented a technical case study about the process of designing and developing Arroyo

Launch School 04/2020 - 02/2022

A mastery-based educational program focusing on software engineering with an emphasis on a deep understanding of fundamentals. Developed a variety of applications using JavaScript, Node.js, Ruby, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, React/Redux, Express, HTML, and CSS, including:

- RequestContainer: A lightweight webhook analysis tool built using MongoDB, PostgreSQL, React, Node.js, and Express
- Krello: A versatile, Kanban-style productivity application built using Node.js, Express, MongoDB, and React/Redux
- MyCart: An intuitive shopping cart application built with MongoDB, React/Redux, Node.js, and Express
- To-do Tracker: A streamlined task-tracking application built using Ruby, Sinatra, and PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

University of Washington

2016 - 2019

Bachelor of Science in Molecular, Cellular, and Developmental Biology